不到20%的人愿意看到
Less than 20% are comfortable
总统和副总统有任何亲属关系
with a president and a vice president being related in any way.
不到10%的人支持从未当选过公职的人
Less than 10% approve of someone who's never held elected office.
但如果我们能扭转局面呢
But if we can move the needle...
提升40个百分点吗
Forty points?
要看我们怎么说
It's how we frame it.
她的支持率不错  比我还高
Her favorables are decent. They're better than mine.
是对人不对事  就她作为联合国大使而言
In a void, but when it comes to her time as the UN ambassador,
支持率就猛跌了
they fall off a cliff.
表现和经验是重要因素
Performance and experience are big factors.
那我们得强调她的优点而非软肋
Then we have to amplify her strengths, not her weaknesses.
我们需要一个有价值的副总统
We're looking for a VP who's an asset.
而这项研究表明她不是
This research proves she isn't.
你的工作不是劝我放弃  而是想办法说服大家
Your job is not to dissuade me, but to figure out how we sell it.
先生  可选的人很多
Sir, there are so many people to choose from.
如果目标是获选
If the goal is to win,
-我们在不遗余力  -赛斯
- and we're bending over backwards-- -Seth.
总统要我们制定计划
The president asked us to develop a plan,
那我们就制定计划
so that's what we'll do.
去我办公室等我
I'll meet you in my office.
-您知道他是对的  -当然了
- You know he's right. - Well, of course he's right.
或许我们可以给她点别的
Maybe we offer something else.
她不会听的
She won't listen.
莉安呢
What about LeAnn?
我也在考虑那个
Yes, I was thinking that, too.
问题是怎么让她配合
Question is how to co-opt her.
她喜欢支票
She likes paychecks.
不  光钱不行  她想要政治影响力
No, it's gotta be more than money. She wants coattails.
我跟克莱尔交换
We swap Claire's for mine.
-竞选经理吗  -我们需要新鲜血液
- Campaign manager? - We could use some fresh blood.
这我同意  但莉安
That I agree with, but LeAnn?
没法保证我们能控制她
I mean, there's no guarantee that we can control her.
但如果她能说服克莱尔改主意
Yeah, but if she can convince Claire to change her mind,
那对我就足够了
that's all I need.
是
Yes.
战况室都等您了  先生
They're ready for you in the Situation Room, sir.
我就过去
I'll be right there.
如果有必要你可以跟她合作
You could work with her if you had to.
我不非得喜欢她才能跟她合作
I don't have to like her to work with her.
-很好  打电话吧  -您还想让赛斯知情吗
- Good, make the call. - You still want Seth on the plan?
是的  直到莉安同意  我需要担心他吗
Yes, until LeAnn's on board. Do I have to worry about him?
我们挖得很深  他的电邮和手机记录里没查到
We dug pretty deep. Nothing in his emails or phone records.
他聪明  知道掩盖踪迹
He's smart enough to cover his tracks.
我去跟他谈谈
I'll talk to him.
-你觉得这幅画如何  -我不知道
- What do you think of this painting? - I'm not sure.
沃克和我有一晚曾坐在这里  盯着这幅画看
Walker and I sat here one night, stared up at a painting,
现在挂在总统办公室的那副蓝色的
the blue one that's in the Oval now.
他们换上了这副
They replaced it with this.
那不是美国国旗
That's not the American flag.
不  是南军的旗
No, it's the rebel flag...
沉入虚无
sinking into oblivion.
那是闪电吗
Is that a lightning bolt?
我以为是的...
Oh, I assume...
除非是想把船画成独角兽还没画好
Unless it's just a bad attempt at making the ship a unicorn.
你看出来了吗
Do you see that?
色彩不错
Colors are nice.
我真不喜欢
I hate it.
那我也不喜欢
I guess I hate it, too.
我想在白宫
I suppose it's not a good idea to have
挂联邦旗大概不是个好主意
the Confederate flag hanging here in the White House
尤其经历了南卡的事
after everything that's happened in South Carolina.
虽然它是在下沉
Even if it is sinking.
你觉得我们该挂什么
What do you think we should put up?
我不知道  您更喜欢的东西
I don't know. Something you like better.
你带那支我签字的马克笔了吗
Do you have that marker I sign things with?
把你的手放在墙上
Put your hand up on the wall.
-先生  -放在墙上
- Sir? - Put it on the wall.
手指伸开一点
Spread your fingers a little bit.
等等  好了
Wait. Okay.
嗯  今天玩到这儿吧
Yeah... That's enough fun for today. -
道格  我不知道该怎么做到他要我做的事
Doug, I don't know how to do what he's asking me to do.
-没有魔法...  -泄露事件
- There is not some magical-- - The leaks.
-是你吗  -你认真的吗
- Was it you? - Are you serious?
非常认真
Very.
我像其他人一样上交了我的通讯
I handed over all of my correspondence, just like everyone else.
那不能证明什么
Doesn't prove anything.
我是在挽救他的竞选
I'm trying to save this campaign.
如果我想搞破坏  让总统自己来就好
If I wanted to sabotage it, I'd let the president do it himself,
而不是在副总统的事上跟他对着干
instead of fighting back on this VP thing.
或许那只是装样子
Or that's just a cover.
去年你不在的时候
I've been in the trenches for the past year
我一直在第一线  现在你还怀疑我
while you've been gone, and now you doubt me?
我不需要这套
I don't need this.
你得到这份工作是靠挖丑事
You got this job by digging up dirt.
如果你到现在还不信任我
If you can't trust me by now,
我不知道我还在这儿干吗
I don't know what I'm doing here.
你是说你想辞职吗
Are you saying you wanna resign?
那是我最不想的了
That is the last thing that I want,
但你没有给我留下的动力
but you're not giving me any incentive to stay.
好吧  去它的
All right. Fuck it.
赛斯  我现在选择信任你
Seth, I'm choosing to believe you right now,
但如果我有一日感到后悔了
but if I come to regret that decision--
你不会的  因为不是我干的
You won't, because it's not me.
我还是认为密查姆有可能
I still think it could be Meechum.
不是他
It wasn't.
-你确定  -完全确定
- You're sure? - I'm positive.
总统也确定
And so is the president.
我可以走了吗
May I go?
还是你想谈谈第一夫人的计划
Or did you want to discuss the plan for the First Lady?
我要打电话  我稍后去你办公室
I have some calls to make. I'll come to your office after.
给我接莉安·哈维
Get me LeAnn Harvey.
米尔金将住在他家  安东·考斯基
Milkin will be staying with this man, Anton Khalski.
他原本拥有俄国
He owned the second-largest
第二大的银行  直到2013年被佩特罗夫查抄
bank in Russia until Petrov seized it in 2013.
考斯基逃出国境去了爱沙尼亚
Khalski fled across the border to Estonia.
我们让米尔金的飞机飞往首都塔林
We'll have Milkin's plane fly to Tallinn,
然后他会乘船去萨拉马考斯基的夏季别墅
then he'll travel by boat to Khalski's summer house on Saaremaa.
明天  我们将结冻米尔金的美国财产
Tomorrow we'll unfreeze Milkin's American assets
并转移到考斯基的瑞士账户
and transfer them to Khalski's Swiss accounts.
考斯基会联络他的俄国军队朋友
Khalski will reach out to his Russian military friends
然后开始收买他们
and then start buying them off.
俄联邦安全局在监控考斯基吗
Are the FSB monitoring Khalski?
密切监控  他们会知道是我们在支持他
Closely. They'll know we're behind this.
-莫斯科如果质问我们呢  -当然是否认
- When Moscow confronts us? - We'll deny, of course.
如果佩特罗夫反应过激  我们是否有所准备
Are we prepared if Petrov overreacts?
第六舰队在博斯普鲁斯海峡附近有部属
The Sixth Fleet has a presence near the Bosphorus,
我们在北海也有巡航
we have patrols in the North Sea.
-起草命令吧  -先生  可以说一句吗
- Draft the order. - Sir, if I may?
-我们讨论过了  凯茜  -是的  先生
- Yeah, we've discussed this, Cathy. - Yes, sir.
我觉得我必须
I feel obligated
要提出强烈的反对  这将给我们带来的外交影响
to raise my very strong objections. The diplomatic cost to us--
如果外交好用
If diplomacy were working,
我们根本就不需要考虑这么做了  是吧
we wouldn't have to consider this course of action, would we?
-我已经提出了担忧  -谢谢大家
- I've voiced my concerns. - Thank you, everyone.
你不会突然让
You're not going to surprise me
总统接电话打我个措手不及吧
by putting the president on, are you?
不  只有我们  但他告诉我了
No, it's just us. He filled me in, though,
-关于第一夫人的要求  -怎么样
- on the First Lady's request. - And?
我们想让你当竞选经理
We wanna make you campaign manager.
看你的邮件
Look at your email.
-是什么  -我们的调研
- What is this? - Our research.
结果是一样的
It all boils down to the same thing.
你们做了几个民调  又如何
You ran a few polls, so what?
-还有焦点小组  -毫无意义
- Focus groups, too. - Meaningless.
这么低的数字可不是毫无意义
Not these numbers.
克莱尔不能参选  你很清楚
Claire can't be on the ticket. You know she can't.
这事不是孤立的
This isn't something you can isolate on its own.
如果油价飙升至6美元/加仑  你们就完了
If gas prices hit $6 a gallon, you're fucked.
-你们会失去所有关键人群  -我们很清楚
- You lose every key demo. - We're well aware.
但如果总统让克莱尔做他的竞选伙伴
But if the president makes Claire his running mate,
那么话题会转向策略而非经济
it makes the conversation tactical instead of economic.
这就给了你们时间处理俄国危机
That buys you time on the Russia crisis.
你们解决了那事  对总统在自信
You solve that, confidence in the president
就能转变成对总统选择的自信
translates into confidence in his choice--
我打给你不是想听你游说  我打来是想给你份工作
I didn't call you to be convinced. I called to offer you a job.
-是为了拆安德伍德夫人的台  -不仅是因为她
- Only to get to Mrs. Underwood. -This isn't just about her.
我们需要你  你能扭转竞选局势
We need you. You'll turn this campaign around.
我好惊讶  道格  我以为你不怎么喜欢我呢
I'm surprised, Doug. I didn't think you were very fond of me.
我喜欢人才  总统也是
I'm fond of talent. So is the president.
我忠于第一夫人
My loyalty is to the First Lady.
我只求你跟她谈谈
All I'm asking is that you talk to her.
这样吧  如果你把我的调查给总统看
I'll tell you what. I'll show Claire your research
我就把你的调查给克莱尔看
if you show the president mine.
这我可以同意
I can agree to that.
我根本不该跟你说话的  海瑟
I shouldn't even be talking to you, Heather.
我非常担忧有滥用职权的现象
I'm seriously concerned that there's been an abuse of power.
司法部长女士  斯坦普先生可以见您了
Madam Attorney General? Mr. Stamper, um, is ready to see you now.
我就去
I'll be right there.
我得挂了
I gotta go.
负责行动的探员
The agent in charge of the operation
事后马上得到了晋升
got a promotion directly after.
-听着  -玛莎  如果总统
- Listen-- - Martha, if the president,
或他的手下  如果有人强迫联调局
or one of his staff... If anyone strong-armed the bureau
追查卢卡斯·古德温
into pursuing Lucas Goodwin,
那你知道  那就是滥用职权
then you know that's an abuse of power.
我就为总统工作
I work for the president.
我正要跟他的幕僚长面谈
I am about to sit down with his Chief of Staff.
-法律就是法律  -这是政治  不是法律
- The law is the law. - This is politics, not the law.
不对  你让我担任
Not true. You brought me on
副检察长是因为我正直
as solicitor general because of my integrity.
而我来找你  是因为你也一样
I am bringing this to you because of yours.
司法部长女士
Madam Attorney General.
我真的得挂了
I really need to go.
如果古德温的故事有一丝真实性
If a sliver of Goodwin's story holds up...
你怎么知道的
How did you even find this?
你的对手研究团队联络过证人保护计划的人吗
Did your oppo team speak to someone in WITSEC?
如果是那样  这种违法行为...
Because if that's the case, then that sort of breach is not--
-我跟他本人谈过  -什么
- I spoke to him myself, personally. - You what?
他来找我的  他找到了我
He came to me. He tracked me down.
我不要沾这事  海瑟
I'm not touching this, Heather.
道格  真是抱歉
Doug, sorry about that.
-没事  -我刚刚在跟首席法官通话
- No-- - I was just on with the Chief Justice.
-没事的  快进来吧  -谢谢
- Don't be silly, come on in. - Thank you.
-这边请  -谢谢你
- This way. - Thanks so much.
我不知道  她作为大使时表现可不怎么样
I don't know. She didn't do that well as ambassador.
经验不够
She wasn't experienced enough.
等等  她做过大使
Hold on, she was an ambassador?
-联合国大使  -克里斯  你不看新闻吗
- At the United Nations. - Chris, don't you watch the news?
你们多少人也有同感
How many of you feel the same?
除了缺乏经验  有其他原因吗
Any other reasons, besides lack of experience?
她在莫斯科情绪失控时很冲动
Well, she was really impulsive when she had that outburst in Moscow.
她根本就不该去
Well, she never should've been there in the first place.
参议院都否决了她
I mean, the Senate voted her down,
她丈夫还是任命了她
and then her husband just appoints her?
哪能这样
That's not right.
瞧  我喜欢她这个人  但我同意
Okay, see, I like her as a person, but I agree,
她该继续做她的第一夫人
she should stick to being First Lady.
他是希望你来劝我放弃
So, he's hoping you'll convince me to let it go.
我能挣得比你给的多得多
Look, I'd make a killing compared to what you've paid me,
但我们谈过要青史留名
but you and I talked about making a real mark.
我父亲真的很喜欢弗兰西斯
My father really liked Francis.
但作为我父亲  我们结婚前一天  他跟我说
But as my daddy, he said to me, the day before we got married,
"你只有一次人生  克莱尔
"You have one life, Claire.
你确定你要跟这个男人共度此生吗"
Are you sure this is the man you wanna spend it with?"
你怎么说的
What did you say?
我说我不想在怀疑中度过人生
I said I didn't want to live my life full of doubts.
我觉得弗兰西斯想让我怀疑自己
Well, I think Francis wants me to doubt myself.
-怎么回事  -我母亲  杀蜥蜴呢
- What was that? - My mother... killing a lizard.
在相当长的一段时间里
-我给您开门  夫人  -我自己能开
- I'll get the door for you, ma'am. - I can open the door myself.
小心脚下  地上有血
Watch your step. There's blood on the floor.
我要你亲自把这个交给总统
I want you to take this to the president, in person.
-如果可以  今晚飞过去  -当然
- Try to get on a plane tonight if you can. - Of course.
这是给你的
This one's for you.
-是温的  -至少是免费的
- It's warm. - At least it's free.
我或许得要你们兑现保险了
I may need to cash in my insurance.
怎么了
What's going on?
如果她拿下提名  我会得到什么位置
Tell me what my position would be if she wins the nomination.
是司法部长吗
Is it the attorney general?
-什么  -算了
- The what? - Never mind.
做竞选伙伴
For running mate?
现在考虑竞选伙伴太早了  他还没赢呢
It's way too early for running mates. He hasn't even won.
-我们说的是一件事吗  -你先说
- Are we talking about the same thing? - You go first.
事不是那么办的
It doesn't work that way.
是你想找工作
Well, you're the one looking for a job.
你要么告诉我
You can either involve me,
要么就等着
or you can start reading
报纸头条报道邓巴泄露婚姻消息
headlines about Dunbar pushing a marriage story.
那会害死你的
That would blow you up.
道格已经起疑了  我没什么可怕的
Doug's already suspicious. I've got nothing to lose.
怎么样
So which is it?
卢卡斯·古德温
Lucas Goodwin.
他是《先驱报》的编辑  是那个...
He was an editor... at The Herald, the one who--
-我们跟他谈过  -他不是在蹲监狱吗
- We spoke to him. - Isn't he in prison?
出来了
Not anymore.
他将于9:30出发
He's scheduled to depart at 0930 hours.
破晓前不久就能到塔林
That'll put him in Tallinn shortly before dawn.
我们的站长与去萨拉马的护送队在待命了
Our station chief is standing by with the escort to Saaremaa.
这是行政命令
This is the executive order.
-长官  -凯茜  我已经决定了
- Sir-- - Cathy, I've made my decision.
-他到达后每小时报告一次  -是  先生
- Hourly updates once he lands. - Yes, sir.
非常感谢
Thank you all very much.
告诉道格我准备好了
Tell Doug I'm ready.
请坐吧  莉安
Please, have a seat, LeAnn.
我很高兴你同意加入了
I'm delighted you've agreed to come on board.
据我所知是有条件的
It's my understanding there is a condition attached.
是的
Well, yes.
她明白这个条件吧  你跟她谈过了
And she understands that condition? You've spoken with her?
抱歉  先生  我没说清楚
Oh, my apologies, sir. I wasn't clear.
我是指我们的条件  不是你们的
I meant our condition, not yours.
在初选日
On Super Tuesday.
这么大老远亲自送来啊
It's a long trip to deliver this in person.
这种东西
Well, it's not the sort of thing
可不能落入旁人手中
you'd want to end up in the wrong hands.
你要留在华盛顿吗
Are you staying here in Washington?
不  我马上回去
No, I'm going straight back.
有什么话需要我带给第一夫人吗
Is there anything you'd like me to tell the First Lady?
告诉她今晚就能回复她
Tell her she'll have her answer by this evening.
-谢谢  总统先生  -一路顺风  哈维小姐
- Thank you, Mr. President. - Have a safe trip back, Ms. Harvey.
我自己出去吧
I'll show myself out.
在相当长的一段时间里  我和总统已经渐渐疏远
For quite some time, the president and I have been growing apart.
让密查姆进来
Have Meechum step in here.
我们曾企图挽救我们的婚姻
We've attempted to save our marriage,
但虽经过很多努力  我最终认识到
but after great effort, I've come to the conclusion
我们的婚姻已不可挽救
that it can't be saved.
我今天很遗憾地宣布
It is with great regret that I announce today
我将申请离婚
I'm filing for divorce.
-我们得阻止她  -在她到机场之前吗
- We have to stop her. - Before she gets to the airport?
不是  克莱尔
No, I mean Claire.
您找我  先生
You asked for me, sir?
进来
Come in.
手机和固话...
Both the cell and the landline--
我们进入了封锁  夫人  我们屏蔽了...
We're on lockdown, ma'am. We had to scramble all the--
封锁  你在说什么呢
Lockdown? What are you talking about?
请您待在房内
I'm gonna need you to stay in the house.
-什么  -抱歉  夫人
- What-- - I'm sorry, ma'am.
你不能强迫我留在屋内
You can't force me to stay in here.
现在有针对您很可信的威胁...
There is a current, highly credible threat to your life--
我要跟你的上级说话
I need to speak to your supervising--
我是您在达拉斯的保安主管  夫人
I am the head of your detail here in Dallas, ma'am,
我得到命令要保护您安全留在屋内
and I've been ordered to keep you securely in this house.
安德伍德2016
安德伍德加油
Go Underwood!
-听啊  -笨蛋伍德  笨蛋伍德
- Listen. - Blunderwood! Blunderwood!
知道他们喊什么吗  "笨蛋伍德"
Do you know what they're chanting? "Blunderwood."
如果我是他们的英语教授
And if I were their English professor,
我会给他们的小聪明打A
why, I would give them all an "A" for cleverness...
但准确性打D
...but a "D" for accuracy.
但做总统就是如此
But that's part of being president.
会树敌
You make enemies,
大家此刻就能听到我的一些敌人在外面呐喊
and you can hear some of mine just outside, right now.
所以我很感激你们每个人
So, I am grateful to each and every one of you
今天前来表示对我的支持
for coming out and showing your support today.
因为你们  我们能拿到提名
It's because of you we will win this nomination,
所以我今天来你们大学
and that's why I came to your college today.
当然了  我知道
Now, of course, I knew
今天会有抗议者来
that there would be protesters here today...
我本可以不来
and I could've chosen not to come,
也可以选择离开时避开他们
or I could choose to avoid them as I leave,
但我不打算那么做
but I'm not going to do that,
因为外面那些学生  你们的同学
because those students out there, your fellow classmates,
我也是他们的总统
I'm their president, too.
不管他们是不是为我投票  我也得带领他们
And whether they vote for me or not, I have to lead them as well.
所以  一定得倾听他们  跟他们说话
So, it's important to hear them, to talk to them,
听他们的想法
to listen to their ideas,
因为就像你们在大学学习
because, just as you're learning in college,
思想的多样化让我们都更加明智
a diversity of ideas makes us all wiser,
对你们的总统来说也是如此
and that holds true even for your president.
真正的领导
True leadership
不是逃避与你意见相左的人
is not running away from those who disagree with you,
而是要接纳他们
but embracing them,
今天结束后  我就打算这么做
and that is exactly what I intend to do when I'm done today.
我要出去接纳那群人
I'm gonna go out and embrace that entire crowd.
我们不该坐军用飞机吗
Shouldn't we be taking a military plane?
那会吸引注意
That would draw attention.
放松
Relax.
一切都安排好了  你不会有事的
Everything's been worked out. You're in good hands.
给  睡会儿吧
Here, get some sleep.
今晚要走很久
It's gonna be a long trip tonight.
笨蛋伍德  笨蛋伍德
Blunderwood! Blunderwood!
-有消息吗  -都安排好了  先生
- Any news? - Everything's secure, sir.
我们爱你  安德伍德
We love you, Underwood!
感谢大家前来
Thank you all for coming out,
包括那些不完全支持我的人
even those of you who don't entirely support me.
-总统你真棒  -谢谢
- Way to go, Mr. President! - Thank you.
我想尽量听听你们究竟反对我什么
I wanna try to hear what it is that you disagree with me about.
我知道不是每个人都支持我
I understand not everyone's for me.
-停止战争  -滚回加夫尼去吧
- No more wars! - Go back to Gaffney!
你好吗  谢谢你能来
Hello, how are you? Thank you for coming out.
你好  谢谢你能来
Hello, thank you for coming out.
-你很棒  -我们知道你的真实面目
- You're doing a great job! - We know what you are!
你好
Hello.
好了  我来是想听听你们的声音
All right, I'm here to try to listen to you,
但是一个一个说可能会比较好
but probably one at a time is gonna be a little better.
也许我们应该进行一对一的对话
Okay, maybe we could have a conversation, more one-on-one.
这样很难听清
It's difficult to hear you.
我知道你们不喜欢什么  但你们支持什么呢
I understand what you don't believe in, but what are you for?
这样问也许比较好  你怎么样
That would be a good question. All right, how about you?
你已经冲我喊了有一会儿了
You've been yelling at me for a little while.
你觉得我该在哪些方面有所改变
What do you think I should be doing differently?
-你应该辞职  -好吧
- You should resign. - Well, now,
我没在请求你们为我投票
I'm not asking for your vote,
但如果你是总统  你会怎么做呢
but what would you do if you were president?
你在毁掉我们的国家
You're ruining our country!
我来这里是想听你们的心声
I came out here to try to listen to what you wanna say,
但如果你们只是一直尖叫下去
but if all you're gonna do is scream--
有枪
Gun!
快走  快走
Let's go! Let's go!
快走  快走  快快快
Move! Move! Go, go, go!
有人企图刺杀总统
There has been an attempted assassination of the president.
弗兰克·安德伍德总统遭到了枪击
President Frank Underwood has been shot.
安德伍德总统遭枪击
哈蒙德大学发生刺杀未遂事件
大约十分钟前发生于华盛顿特区
It occurred about ten minutes ago during a campaign event
哈蒙德大学的一场竞选活动中
at Hammond University in Washington, D.C.
我们尚不清楚总统的伤情
We do not yet know how severely the president has been wounded.
他正在被送往杰弗逊纪念医院
He is en route to Jefferson Memorial Hospital.
我们不知道他的情况有多严重
We don't know how serious his condition may be.
刺杀未遂事件的视频还没送到
Footage of the assassination attempt is still making its way to us,
但相信很快能够公布
and we expect to have that shortly.
目击者声称
Witnesses are reporting
当时有连续好几声枪响
that there was a quick succession of gunshots,
约有四五发
four or five,
枪手是一个人  身份还未确认
a lone gunman whose identity we are still trying to determine.
已得知枪手已被击毙
We've been told the gunman was killed,
另有至少一名特勤人员遇难
as well as at least one Secret Service agent,
但我们还未得到明确证实
but we don't have definitive confirmation of that yet.
我们也不清楚枪手和特勤人员的身份
We don't yet know who the gunman may be or who the agent is.
-怎么了  -总统遇刺了
- What's happened? - The president's been shot.
导播现在告诉我
I'm hearing now that the president
总统至少腹部中了一枪  也许不止
received at least one gunshot to the abdomen, possibly more,
他紧捂腹部
that he clutched his stomach,
立即倒地
that he fell instantly to the ground,
现场尖叫连连  人群陷入恐慌
and there were screams, people panicking,
场面十分混乱
that it has been very chaotic at that scene.
目前我们获得的消息很有限
We have very little information at this time,
仅知道总统遭遇枪击受伤
other than shots were fired, the president wounded.
但如我所言  他还活着
But as I say, he is alive.
我们也还没得到
We've gotten no official
白宫的官方声明
statement from the White House as of yet,
不了解总统的具体情况
either the president's precise condition
或是布莱斯副总统的行踪
or the whereabouts of Vice President Blythe.
有消息称他目前正在白宫  但我们还不能确认
He is believed to be at the White House. We cannot confirm that,
我们也不清楚他是否会出任代总统
nor do we know if he will take over as acting president,
履行宪法第25条修正案
assuming the duties of the presidency
规定的总统职责
under the terms of the 25th Amendment to the Constitution.
但如果总统的伤势
That would seem likely, however,
如我们认为的那样严重
if the president's wounds are as serious
这将很有可能
as we believe them to be.
这是国家的艰难时刻
This is a difficult moment for the country.
这不是我国总统第一次遇刺
It is not the first time that a president has been shot
我和很多人此前都曾经历过
in my lifetime or in many of yours.
但即便是那些经历过这种事的人
But even for those of us who have experienced this before,
此事仍触目惊心  骇人听闻
it is no less of a shock, it is no less terrifying.
这是检验我国坚韧的时刻
It is the moment when our nation's resilience,
检验人民团结的时刻
when our collective strength,
最能检验一切的时刻
the moment when all of that is tested the most.
我们难以想象
And we can only imagine
第一夫人此时多么痛苦
how difficult it must be for the First Lady.
-弗兰西斯他...  -迈克尔说了
- Francis-- - Michael told me.
我得回华盛顿
I have to go back to Washington.
那你还耽搁什么
Well, what are you waiting for?
还指望我安慰你吗
Do you expect me to console you?
不  我只是...
No, I just...
-再见  母亲  -克莱尔
- Goodbye, Mother. - Claire.
我希望他死
I hope he dies.
克莱尔  我无法想象你多么难过
Claire, I can't imagine how difficult this must be.
需要我帮忙吗
Is there anything I can do?
谢谢你来电慰问  副总统先生
I appreciate the call, Mr. Vice President,
但你目前肯定还有许多事得处理
but I'm sure you've got a lot to take care of right now.
你需要我的帮助吗
Is there anything I can do to help you?
一旦我们弄清
I'll be making a brief appearance
目前的状况  我就会进行简短发言
once we have a better sense of... where things stand.
需要我在场吗
Would you like me to be there?
这样最好  让国家见到第一夫人
I think it would be good, the country seeing the First Lady.
我觉得让他们见到你临危不乱更重要
I think it's more important that they see your steady hand.
如果你在我身边  我会更有底气
If you're by my side, it would certainly make it steadier.
当然  我都听你的
Of course. Anything you ask.
我会为你们祈祷  为你们俩
I'm gonna be praying for you. For both of you.
谢谢  唐
Thank you, Don.
好了
Okay.
这边  先生
This way, sir.
总统  2014年10月30日
谢谢  先生
Thank you, sir.
有高度机密事务
The acting president needs
需要向代总统报告
to be briefed on a highly classified matter.
没有军事机密许可的人请离开房间
Everyone without military clearance, we'll need the room.
枪手开了两枪
It was in fact two shots.
袭击者确认死亡
安德伍德在杰弗逊纪念医院
刺杀未遂事件
一枪擦伤了身体  就在右臂之下
One that grazed the torso just beneath the right arm
另一枪射入了腹部
and the second which entered the abdomen,
多半伤了肝脏
possibly into his liver.
显然是这一枪造成了最严重的伤害
Obviously, it was that shot that did the greatest damage.
据悉  总统目前情况危急
The president is currently reported to be in critical condition.
为保护总统遇害的
The Secret Service agent
特勤局特工名叫艾德华·密查姆
that was killed protecting the president was Edward Meechum.
他是总统安保队队长
He is the head of the president's detail,
我们现在可以确定
and we can confirm that now.
他中枪后  在死前
After being shot and before he died,
杀死了身份仍未知的袭击者
he killed the assailant whose identity is still unknown.
我们正等待白宫新闻发言人赛斯·格雷森的
We're waiting now on a press conference from the White House
新闻发布会
from Press Secretary Seth Grayson,
发布会稍后就会举行
and we expect to have that beginning in just a few moments.
先给我看过两遍  再对外确认
We confirm nothing unless you run it past me twice first,
-我不希望...  -格雷森先生...
- I don't want-- - Mr. Grayson...
马上过去  不要有任何传言  只要事实
I'm on my way. We don't want any rumors, only facts.
一名学生宣称是特勤局的人
There's a student who's claiming it was the Secret Service
-开的第一枪  -我刚说了什么
- who fired the first shot. - What did I just say?
-别拿这种屁话浪费我时间  -先生
- Do not waste my time with that bullshit. - Sir,
媒体在等了
the press is waiting.
行  我马上过去  我的...
All right, I'm... I'm coming. Uh, where's my...
今日午后12点38分  副总统唐纳德·布莱斯
At 12:38 this afternoon, Vice President Donald Blythe
由内阁任命为代总统
was authorized as acting president by the cabinet.
目前他正与内阁会面
He is currently meeting with them.
约20分钟前  第一夫人在安德鲁空军基地降落
Approximately 20 minutes ago, the First Lady landed at Andrews.
她不久就会达到医院
She is expected to arrive at the hospital shortly.
-安德伍德夫人  -他怎么样
- Mrs. Underwood. - How is he?
他们还在手术室里  大概还得要几小时
They're still in the OR. Probably a few hours left to go.
他能保住命吗
Is he going to live?
他被直接击中肝脏  肝脏部分破裂
He took a direct hit to his liver, which is partially shattered.
幸运的是  左叶有一部分几乎完好无损
Fortunately, part of the left lobe is mostly intact.
我们认为  他有很大几率挺过手术
Now, we think there's a decent chance he will survive surgery,
但即便如此  真正的难关在术后才开始
but even if he does, that's when the real fight begins.
我想见他
I'd like to see him.
他一结束我就告诉您
As soon as he's out, I'll make sure you know.
好  谢谢
Okay, thank you.
我建议取消这次行动
I'd recommend we call off this operation,
现在就让飞机调头
we turn the plane around now.
我不同意  我们精心计划过了
I disagree. It's well planned.
而且总统已经签字了
The president already signed off.
总统可能撑不过去
The president might die.
-国务卿女士  -不准这样说  凯茜
- Madam Secretary... - We'll have no talk like that, Cathy.
抱歉  先生
My apologies, sir.
我想说的是
What I am trying to say is that
针锋相对的风险太大了
it is too risky to antagonize--
我们的目的是吓唬他们  不是
The point was to scare them, not--
在最高指挥官
To do anything of this nature
无法工作时做这种事情
while the commander in chief is incapacitated,
-俄国人会利用这时机  -我们现在高度警戒
- the Russians will take advantage-- - We're at high alert.
我们准备好面对一切不测了
We're prepared for all eventualities.
不能把军队当成故障保险
We don't want the military to be the fail-safe here.
副...总统先生
Mr. Vice... Mr. President...
我认为  执行总统签署的命令
I believe it is our duty to carry out the orders
是我们的职责
that the president signed.
-情况已经变了  -计划依然可行
- The circumstances have changed. - The plan is sound.
您想让我怎么办  先生
So, what would you like to do, sir,
继续还是终止任务
continue the mission or abort?
我想再考虑考虑
Uh, I... I wanna think on it.
按计划他将在两小时后降落
He's scheduled to land in two hours.
我只想
I just want...
我得考虑一下  我们休息一下吧
I've gotta think. Let's take a break.
我得整理整理思绪
I, uh, I need to process all this.
先生
Sir?
总统权衡过一切
The president weighed everything--
凯茜说得很有道理
Cathy brought up some good points.
她从最开始就反对这件事
She's been against this from the very beginning,
但总统明确
but the president clearly--
给我点时间  道格  求你了
Just give me some time, Doug, please?
在我耳边吼的人太多了
I've got too many people barking in my ear.
总统已经做完手术
The president is out of surgery,
他病情稳定但依然危重
and he is in stable but critical condition.
听我说  听我说  我们要有序得来
Excuse me! Excuse me! We are going to keep this orderly.
先让萨克逊医生发表完声明
Dr. Saxon will finish his statement,
然后我们再回答你们的问题  谢谢
and then we'll answer your questions. Thank you.
手术进行了6小时28分钟
The surgery lasted six hours, 28 minutes.
切除了四分之三的肝脏
Three quarters of his liver was removed.
肝脏  哪怕只剩四分之一
A liver, even one quarter of a liver,
都有能力在六至八周内再生
has the ability to regenerate within six to eight weeks.
我们每小时都会对他进行血检
We will be conducting blood tests every hour.
监测肝酶水平  血氨水平  凝血酶原时间
Enzymes, ammonia levels, PT times,
这些在声明单上都有说明
I believe these are all explained in the handout.
《华盛顿先驱报》提供照片
...医学报告  我们马上就继续
...the medical report, live from the White House,
白宫的现场直播
which we will return to shortly.
但我们在密切关注一则重大新闻
But we have breaking news we're following.
在之前的报道中  刺客被认为是
The would-be assassin was previously reported
俄亥俄州代顿的约翰·卡莱尔
as John Carlyle from Dayton, Ohio,
但现在司法部的消息源称
but sources in the Department of Justice now say
这其实是卢卡斯·古德温的化名
this was actually an alias for Lucas Goodwin,
他曾是《华盛顿先驱报》的编辑
a former editor at The Washington Herald
两年前被判犯下了网络恐怖主义罪
who was convicted of cyberterrorism nearly two years ago.
如果我们暂停这段手机拍摄的枪击视频
Now, if we freeze this cell phone footage of the shooting
然后将枪手的脸与古德温的照片进行的对比
and we compare the shooter's face to this picture of Goodwin...
目击者录像
比照惊人
well, the comparison is striking
似乎也证实了
and would seem to confirm
来自司法部消息源的说法
what we're hearing from our sources in the DOJ,
即古德温已于近日获释
who say Goodwin was recently released
并加入了证人保护计划
and is in a witness protection program.
感觉好怪  想到我...
It's so strange to think that I--
多久  那就是两小时前吧  还不到
It was, what? Just two hours before? Less than.
他是什么反应
How did he react?
他很冷漠吧  我看不透他
He was cold, I guess. I couldn't really read him.
他看起来好虚弱
He looks so weak.
我应该回华盛顿吗
Should I come back to Washington?
看看接下来几天的情况吧
Let's see how the next couple of days go.
随时通知我  我立马上飞机
Well, just say the word, I'm on a plane.
好吧  谢谢  莉安  晚安
All right, thank you, LeAnn. Good night.
晚安
Good night.
弗兰西斯  能听到吗
Francis, can you hear me?
弗兰西斯
Francis.
我刚跟艾迪的父母谈了  夫人
I just spoke to Eddie's parents, ma'am.
您说您想给他们打电话
You said you wanted to call them?
是的  谢谢
Yes, thank you.
艾德华不止是位英雄  密查姆太太
Edward was more than a hero, Mrs. Meechum.
他是我们的朋友
He was our friend.
我非常遗憾您失去了儿子
I'm so sorry for your loss.
如果有什么我能为您
Please, let me know if there's anything
和您的家人做的  务必告诉我
I can do for you and your family.
您随时可以给我打电话
You can call me anytime.
是的  太太  这是我的私人号码
Yes, ma'am, that is my private number.
我再次深表遗憾
And again, I'm so sorry.
-卢卡斯·古德温  -我们不知道他出狱了
- Lucas Goodwin? - We didn't know he was out.
怎么可能  他被释放了你却不知道
How can that happen? He's released and you didn't know--
夫人  说到威胁
Ma'am... as far as threats go,
我们最近几乎都在忙着应付您
we've been far more occupied with you lately.
我希望我们能合作  因为我需要您的帮助
I'm hoping that we can work together, because I need your help.
-怎么帮  -副总统
- How? - The vice president.
我们谈过了  我告诉他我会陪他出面
We spoke. I told him I would appear with him.
不是声明的事
Not the statement.
他现在有个决定难以定夺
He's having trouble making a decision.
您能跟我一起回白宫吗
Can you come back to the White House with me?
这事很严重  夫人
It's serious, ma'am.
我可以在路上跟您说明情况
I can fill you in on the way.
我去拿我的东西
I'll grab my things.
我不能让你进去  先生
I can't let you go any farther, sir.
我是他的幕僚长
I'm his Chief of Staff.
抱歉  先生
I'm sorry, sir.
现在只有医生和第一夫人可以进去
Only doctors and the First Lady for now.
克莱尔
Claire.
你好
Hello.
你好吗
How are you?
-累坏了  -肯定的
- Exhausted. - I'm sure.
你也一定累坏了
You must be, too.
有太多东西我不了解  快把我...搞晕了
There's so much I don't know. It's... overwhelming.
先生  我已向第一夫人说明了米尔金行动
Sir, I briefed the First Lady on the Milkin operation.
考虑到她曾与俄国有过直接交涉
I thought she might have some insight,
我想也许她会有一些见解
given her experience working directly with Russia.
我知道已经有很多人为你出谋划策了
I know you've had a lot of people weigh in already.
我重视你的建议  克莱尔  我很高兴你能来
I value your input, Claire. I'm glad you're here.
-道格拉斯  能让我们单独谈谈吗  -当然
- Douglas, will you give us a minute? - Of course.
我会跟内阁在一起  先生
I'll be with the cabinet, sir.
你知道人们常说
You know that thing that people say,
上帝不会让你无法承受
"God never gives you more than you can handle"?
知道
Yes.
我的玛乔莉  愿主保佑她
My Marjory, God bless her,
她说那是屁话
she said that was pure bullshit.
你丈夫正在与死神搏斗
Oh, listen to me complaining
你还得听我抱怨
while your husband is fighting for his life.
没关系  其实我需要分散下注意
Oh, it's okay. Actually, I need the distraction.
我们谈谈俄国吧
Let's talk Russia.
我很纠结  我们有架飞机在北海上空盘旋
I'm torn. Uh, we have this plane circling over the North Sea...
-我不知道该怎么做  -你的直觉是什么
- and I don't know what to do. - Well, what does your gut tell you?
我从来就不是靠直觉做事的人
I've never been a gut sort of guy.
如果有把枪指在我头上...
I mean, if I had a gun to my head...
-对不起  我比喻不当  - 没关系  继续
- Sorry, that was a poor choice of words. - It's fine. Go on.
我理解总统希望达到什么
I understand what the president hoped to achieve,
但一想到激怒俄国...
but the thought of provoking Russia...
我这才刚开始了解此事的复杂性
And I'm just beginning to immerse myself in all the complexities.
如果换了弗兰克  他会怎么做呢
What would Frank do, if he were in my shoes right now?
如果他在这儿  他会告诉你
If he were here, he'd tell you
那是你最不应该考虑的事
that's the last thing you should think about,
因为他不在这儿  你在
because he's not here, you are.
你会怎么做
What would you do?
继续这项任务还是叫他回来
Proceed with the mission or bring him back?
两者我都不喜欢
I don't like either.
我只有这两个选择
Those are my options.
如果说在弗兰西斯身边28年  我学到了什么
Well, if there's one thing I've learned, 28 years with Francis,
那就是他重复多次的那句话
and he said it time and time again,
"如果你不喜欢餐具的摆放..."
"If you don't like the way the table is set..."
-"那就掀桌子"  -没错
- "Then turn over the table." - That's right.
他跟我说过不止一次
He's said it to me, more than once.
那么你就应该这么做  唐纳德
Then that's what you should do, Donald.
-但要怎么做呢  -我们一起想想吧
- But how? - Well, let's figure it out.
我们不是早该降落了吗
Weren't we supposed to have landed already?
-我们在待命航线上  -为什么  出什么事了吗
- We're in a holding pattern. - Why? Is something wrong?
我只知道我们在待命航线上
All I know is we're in a holding pattern.
道格
Doug.
这架飞机很快就会没油
This plane's gonna run out of fuel soon.
我们一定要找个地方让它降落
We're gonna have to put it down somewhere.
我马上就发声明  先跟记者团打声招呼吧
I'll be making a statement shortly. Let's notify the press corps.
-关于行动吗  -不  让美国人民放心
- About the operation? - No, to reassure the American people.
-我在那边等你吗  -给我十分钟
- Shall I meet you in there? - Ten minutes.
内阁怎么样
The cabinet?
-还在等您的决定  先生  -很好
- Still waiting on your decision, sir. - Good.
走吧
Let's go.
把飞机降落在中国
I want you to land the plane in China.
中国吗  先生
China, sir?
没有中国的钱就没有救市计划
There's no bailout without Chinese money.
我们把米尔金给他们  他们会有更多筹码
We give them Milkin, they have more leverage.
先生  那就放弃我们的筹码了
Sir, that gives away our leverage.
我不赞成政权更迭  但那是...
I'm not for regime change, but that just...
这是佩特罗夫最想不到的事
It's the last thing that Petrov is expecting.
他们会要求东西伯利亚的钻井权
They'll demand drilling access in eastern Siberia.
等他们提出  我们就是两害中较轻的那个
And when they do, we become the lesser of two evils.
先生  总统从未打算
Sir, at no time did the president
把中国搅进来...
intend on bringing China into the mix...
让飞机降落在中国领土上
Get the plane on Chinese soil.
并且移交米尔金的资产  这就是我的决定
And turn over Milkin's assets. That's my decision.
-我是向你求助的  -我也给予了帮助
- I asked for your help. - And that's what I gave.
不  中国不在总统的计划范围内
No, China wasn't part of the president's plan.
它在代总统的计划范围内
It's part of the acting president's plan.
-你准备好了吗  -好了  就等你了
- You ready? - Yes, whenever you are.
-赛斯  -是  先生
- Seth? - Yes, sir.
女士们先生们  有请代总统
Ladies and gentlemen, the acting president.
请坐
Please, sit.
今天对所有美国民众来说都是艰难的一天
This is a difficult day for all Americans,
特别是安德伍德夫人
particularly for Mrs. Underwood,
很感谢她能来到这儿
who is gracious enough to be here,
在我向焦虑的国民讲话时  给我力量
to lend me strength while I address an anxious nation.
总统先生
Mr. President!